William Edgar Borah Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Office File, 1907-1940 (Box 1-528)
  - 1937
    - Legislation (Box 472)
      - Reorganization program
      - Repeal of 14th Amendment
      - Robinson-Patman bill
      - Sales tax
      - S. 1233
      - S. 2670
      - S.2849, Borah
      - Social Security Act
      - Tydings bill (Box 476)
      - T.V.A. bill
      - Utilities, power matters
      - U.S. Court of Appeals
      - Wagner bill
    - Letters of introduction
    - Levinson, Salmon O.
    - Library of Congress
    - Lists
    - Manuscripts, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 477)
    - Marine Corps
    - Minidoka project
    - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Monopoly
    - National (Box 478)
      - Emergency Council
      - Park Service
      - Resources Board
      - Youth Administration
    - Nationalization
    - Navy Department
    - Nazism, (2 folders)
    - Newspapers, (1 folder) (Box 479)
    - Nuts, Idaho
    - Pardons and paroles
    - Party matters
    - Patents
    - Patronage, appointments
      - Arney, C. E.
      - Black, Hugo LaFayette, (2 folders)
      - Burk, Harold
      - Circuit, judgeship
      - Commissioner of Reclamation
      - Cook, Edgar J.
      - Garnett appointment
      - Miscellaneous
      - Murrah for district judge, Idaho
    - Pension legislation (Box 480)
    - Personal
    - Political
      - Copeland
      - Idaho
      - Mid-convention
      - Miscellaneous
    - Post Office Department
    - President's term, change of
    - Public Roads
    - Public Works Administration, insurance
    - Railroad Retirement Board
    - Railroads, legislation
    - Reconstruction Finance Corp. (Box 481)
    - Request for
      - Articles
      - Photographs
      - Speech on Fascism, (3 folders)
      - Speeches
    - Robins, Raymond
    - Robinson, Frank D., (2 folders)
    - Rockwell, Irvin E. (Box 482)
    - Rural Electrification Administration
    - Russia
    - School districts
    - Security Exchange Commission
    - Seed Loan bill
    - Shipstead, Henrik
    - Silver
    - Social Security, (2 folders)
    - South American Conference
    - South Fork Reservoir
    - Speeches (Box 483)
    - State Department, (2 folders)
    - Strikes
      - Automobiles
      - Maritime
      - Miscellaneous
    - Supreme Court, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 484)
    - Tariff, Reciprocal Trade Agreement
    - Taxes, undistributed profit
    - Taxation
      - Community tax
      - Miscellaneous
    - Treasury Department
    - Unemployment (Box 485)
    - United States Employees' Compensation, (2 folders)
    - Veterans Administration
    - Wage increase
    - War Department, (3 folders)
    - Washburn, Robert M.
    - West Point, N. Y., United States Military Academy
    - Works Progress Administration
  - 1938 (Box 486)
    - Agriculture, general
    - Agriculture
      - Apples
      - Beans
      - Corn hog contracts
      - Noxious weeds
      - Potatoes
      - Sugar beets
      - Wheat
      - Wool
    - Annapolis, Md., United States Naval Academy, (2 folders)
    - Antilynching bill speech, (4 folders) (Box 487)
    - Appointments, Borah
    - Appropriations
      - Miscellaneous
      - Venereal disease
    - Archives
    - Articles, (2 folders)
    - Automobile strike investigation
    - Bank legislation
    - Biological Survey
    - Black Canyon Irrigation District, Idaho (Box 488)
    - Blister rust control
    - Boise Valley supplementary water supply
    - Cache National Forest
    - Cement
    - Census, Bureau of
    - Charity
    - Civil Conservation Corps
    - Civil Service Commission
    - Claims
    - Comments on speeches
    - Commerce Department
    - Committee, Judiciary
    - Commodity Credit Corp.
    - Condolences
    - Congratulations
    - Congressional Library
    - Congressional Record (Box 489)
    - Cooperative Loan Corporation
    - Crank mail
    - Crime situation, District of Columbia
    - Cummings, Homer L.
    - Currency, money question
    - Depletion of mines
    - Depressed crop reports
    - Documents, (2 folders)
    - Equal Rights Amendment
    - Farm credit
    - Farm Security Administration
    - Federal buildings
    - Federal Communications Commission
    - Federal Home Loan Bank Board (Box 490)
    - Federal Housing Administration
    - Federal Land banks
    - Federal Power Commission
    - Federal Reserve Bank
    - Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation
    - Fisheries
    - Food and Drug Administration
    - Foreign affairs
      - Argentine Sanitary Convention
      - British and Canadian trade agreements
      - Hungary
      - Jewish affair
      - Mexico
      - Miscellaneous, ( 2 folders)
      - Reciprocal Trade Agreement, (2 folders) (Box 491)
      - War situation, (2 folders)
    - Forest reserves
    - Forest Service, (2 folders)
    - General Accounting Office
    - General information, (2 folders) (Box 492)
    - General Land Office
    - Geological Survey
    - Government Printing Office
    - Hague, Mayor
    - Henry's Fork
    - Home Owners Loan Corp.
    - Illness, letters concerning
    - Immigration
    - Indian affairs, (2 folders)
    - Internal Revenue (Box 493)
    - International Joint Commission
    - Interstate Commerce Commission
    - Introduction, letters of, (2 folders)
    - Invitations (by state)
      - Alabama-Iowa, (11 folders)
      - Kansas-Wisconsin, (30 folders) (Box 494)
    - Justice Department
    - LaVatta, Charles E.
    - Legislation
      - Actors' bill
      - Amending Johnson Act
      - Amending Pope-McGill Act (Box 495)
      - Antilynching bill, (2 folders)
      - Aviation
      - Black-Connery Wage Hour bill
      - Board of Tax Appeals, abolishment of
      - Borah S. Res. 221
      - Borah S. Res. 229
      - Boycotting
      - Burke bill
      - Car limit bill
      - Child labor
      - Civilian bombing
      - Copeland bill (S. 3078)
      - Creation of additional judgeship
      - Deportation of aliens
      - Dies bill
      - Equal Rights Amendment
      - Farm bill
      - Fingerprinting
      - Food and Drug bill
      - General Welfare Act
      - Gillette bill
      - Harrison-Fletcher bill (Box 496)
      - House Joint Resolution 389
      - H.R. 9050
      - Housing bill
      - Idaho judgeship, creation of
      - Immigration
      - Liquor
      - Ludlow Amendment
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Moratorium for assessment work on mines
      - Naval bill
      - Neely bill, (2 folders) (Box 497)
      - Patent laws, amendment to
      - Patman bill
      - Pettengill bill, (3 folders)
      - Philippine travel pay bill
      - Phosphate
      - Pipe lines
      - Post Office Department
      - Railroad interests, reduction of (Box 498)
      - Refugees
      - Reorganization bill
      - Sheppard-Hill bill
      - Social Security Act
      - Spanish-American War pension
      - Taxicab insurance
      - Tennessee Valley Authority investigation
      - United States Court of Appeals
      - Wagner Act
      - Wagner-Healy bills
    - Letters of introduction
    - Levinson, S.O.
    - Library of Congress
    - Mckaig, Ray
    - Manuscripts
      - Jan.-Feb.
      - Mar.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 499)
    - Marine Corps
    - Milner Low-Lift Irrigation District
    - Milton, John, unseating of
    - Mines, (3 folders)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Jan.-June, (2 folders)
      - July-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 500)
    - Monopoly positions
    - Mooney, Tom, pardon of
    - National Labor Relations Board
    - National Park Service
    - Naturalization
    - Navigation Bureau
    - Navy
    - Newspapers, ( 4 folders)
    - Noxious weeds
    - Oil investigations (Box 501)
    - Pardons and paroles
    - Patents
    - Patronage, appointments
      - Civil Aeronautics Authority Board
      - Clarke, Judge, Circuit Court of Appeals
      - Cook, Edgar J.
      - Interstate Commerce Commission
      - Miscellaneous
      - Supreme Court
    - Pension legislation
    - Personal, (3 folders)
    - Political (Box 502)
      - Campaign expenditures
      - Idaho, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous
      - Personal
    - Positions, requests for, A-Y, (6 folders)
    - Post Office, (2 folders) (Box 503)
    - Public roads
    - Pump-Priming bill
    - Railroad legislation
    - Railroad Retirement Board
    - Reconstruction Finance Corp., (2 folders)
    - Reclamation, Bureau of, (3 folders) (Box 504)
    - Relief money, speech relating to intoxicating liquor
    - Requests for
      - Articles
      - Photographs
      - Speeches
    - Robins, Raymond
    - Rockwell, Irvin E.
    - Rural Electrification Administration
    - Securities and Exchange Commission
    - Silver
    - Social Security, (2 folders) (Box 505)
    - Soil conservation
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, Washington, D.C.
    - State Department, (3 folders)
    - Stotts, James R.
    - Sugar
    - Tariff
    - Tariff Commission
    - Taxation
    - Taxing state securities
    - Treasury
    - Unemployment and relief
    - Upper Snake River
    - U.S. Employees' Compensation Commission
    - Veterans Administration (Box 506)
    - Wage and Hour bill, (5 folders)
    - War Department
    - War question
    - Weather Bureau
    - West Point, N.Y., United States Military Academy
    - Works Progress Administration, (4 folders) (Box 507)
  - 1939 (Box 508)
    - Administrative law
    - Aeronautics
    - Agriculture Department
    - Agriculture
      - Beans
      - Phosphate
      - Potatoes
      - Sugar Beets
      - Wheat
    - Appointments with Borah
    - Appropriations, (4 folders)
    - Articles, granted (Box 509)
    - Bank legislation
    - Bergdoll, Grover Cleveland
    - Biological Survey
    - Bureau of Census
    - Bureau of Fisheries
    - Bureau of Immigration
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs
    - Bureau of Mines, (2 folders)
    - Bureau of Naturalization
    - Bureau of Patents
    - Bureau of Public Roads (Box 510)
    - Bureau of Reclamation, (4 folders)
    - Carey Act project
    - Charity
    - City of Rocks
    - Civil Liberties bill (Box 511)
    - Civil Service Commission
    - Civilian Conservation Corps
    - Claims
    - Comments on speeches
    - Commerce Departments
    - Committee, Judiciary
    - Commodity Credit Corp.
    - Congratulation
    - Congressional Library list
    - Congressional Record
    - Conservation Board (Box 512)
    - Currency, money question
    - Documents, (2 folders)
    - Farm credit
    - Farm credit Administration
    - Farm Security Administration
    - Federal buildings
    - Federal Communications Commission
    - Federal Home Loan Bank Board
    - Federal Housing Administration
    - Federal Land Bank
    - Federal Power Commission
    - Federal Surplus Commodity Corp.
    - Federal Trade Commission
    - Food and drug
    - Foreign affairs
      - Argentine beef
      - Argentine Sanitary Treaty (Box 513)
      - British and Canadian Trade agreements
      - Guam
      - Ludlow Amendment
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Neutrality, (2 folders)
      - Palestine, Jews
      - Reciprocal trade agreements, (1 folder) (Box 514)
      - Reciprocal trade agreements with Chile
      - Repeal of immigration law
      - Royal visit
      - Spanish embargo
      - Treaty relations with Japan
      - War situation
    - Foreign letters
    - Forest reserves
    - Forest Service
    - Free speech, radio
    - General, (2 folders) (Box 515)
    - General Land Office
    - Geological Survey
    - Government Printing Office
    - Hitler, Adolph, speech
    - Home Owners Loan Corp.
    - Immigration
    - Interior Department
    - Internal Revenue
    - Interstate Commerce Commission
    - Invitations (by state)
      - California-Idaho, (5 folders)
      - Illinois-Wisconsin, (24 folders) (Box 516)
    - Justice Department
    - Labor Department
    - Legislation
      - Abolishing Board of Tax Appeals
      - Antilynching bill
      - Antitrust
      - Civil Service Commission
      - Coal
      - Copyright
      - Education
      - Farm legislation (Box 517)
      - Food and Drug Act
      - H.R. 4101
      - Immigration, alien actors
      - Interstate Commerce Commission
      - Labor Relations Act
      - Licensing
      - Long and short haul
      - Martin bill
      - Medical profession
      - Miscellaneous, (4 folders)
      - Neely bill (Box 518)
      - Patent laws, amendment to
      - Patman bill
      - Philippine travel
      - Pipelines
      - Post Office
      - Refugee children
      - Reorganization bill
      - Social Security acts, (2 folders)
      - Tariff investigation
      - Tax exemption securities
      - Transfer of U.S. Employment Service
      - Veterans
      - Wage and hour
    - Letters of appreciation
    - Letters of condolence
    - Letters of introduction, (2 folders) (Box 519)
    - Levinson, Salmon O.
    - McKaig, Ray
    - Manuscripts, (2 folders)
    - Merchant marine
    - Mexico
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders); (7 folders) (Box 520, Box 521)
    - National Archives Council
    - National Labor relations
    - National Youth Administration
    - Nazism and free speech
    - Neutrality
      - After Declaration of War by England and France, (2 folders)
      - After White House Conference
      - Legislation (Box 522)
      - Speech
    - Newspapers, (3 folders)
    - Notices, Works Project Administration
    - Oil
    - Paroles and pardons
    - Patronage, appointments
      - Interstate Commerce Commission
      - Miscellaneous (Box 523)
      - National Labor Relations Board
      - Supreme Court
    - Pension legislation, (2 folders)
    - Personal, (2 folders)
    - Philippines, annexation of
    - Political
      - Idaho
      - Miscellaneous
      - Personal
      - Third term (Box 524)
    - Post Office Department
    - Public Works Administration
    - Railroad legislation
    - Reconstruction Finance Corp.
      - Photographs
      - Speeches, (2 folders)
    - Robins, Raymond (Box 525)
    - Rockwell, Irvin E.
    - Rural Electrification Administration
    - Securities and Exchange Commission
    - Silver
    - Snake River, (2 folders)
    - Social Security, (3 folders)
    - Soil conservation
    - Spanish embargo
    - State Department, (1 folder) (Box 526)
    - Stotts, James R.
    - Strikes, Chrysler
    - Sugar
    - Swayne, Samuel F.
    - Tariff, whole oil
    - Taxation
      - Miscellaneous
      - Oils, fats
    - Townsend Plan
    - Trade with Japan
    - Treasury Department
    - U.S. Employees' Compensation Commission
    - Veterans Administration (Box 527)
    - Wage and Hour Division
    - War Department
    - Washburn, R. M.
    - West Point, N.Y., United States Military Academy, (3 folders)
    - Works Progress Administration, (1 folder) (Box 528)
  - 1940
    - Appropriations
    - Articles, requested
    - Civil Service Commission
    - Commerce Department
    - Committee on Foreign relations
    - Committee on the Judiciary
    - Condolences
    - Congressional Record
    - Documents
    - Farm Credit Administration
      - Finland
      - Miscellaneous
      - Reciprocal Trade Agreement
      - Treaty with Japan
    - Foreign letters
    - General Accounting Office
    - Invitations
      - District of Columbia
      - New York
      - Wisconsin
    - Legislation
      - Antilynching
      - Miscellaneous
      - Post Office
      - S. 517
      - S. Res. 160
      - Wagner Health bill
    - Miscellaneous
    - Newspapers
    - Political file, third term
    - Railroad Retirement Board
    - Securities and Exchange Commission
    - Social Security
    - Taxation, gas and oil
    - U.S. Employees' Compensation Commission
    - War Department
    - Works Project Administration
- Land Utilization File, 1909-1935 (Box 529-581)
  Letters received and carbons of letters sent.
  Arranged chronologically by year, alphabetically by subject within, and therein chronologically by month.
  - 1909 (Box 529)
  - 1912
    - Homesteads
    - Minidoka, Idaho, projects
  - 1913-1914
    - Angeles Forest Case No. 425
    - Blackfoot Land Office
    - Boise Land Office, Boise, Idaho
    - Boise, Idaho, project
    - Carey lands
    - Coeur D'Alene Land Office, Coeur D'Alene, Idaho
    - Conservation, miscellaneous
    - Contests, (3 folders) (Box 530)
    - Denver Irrigation Conference, Denver, Colo.
    - Desert entries, (3 folders)
    - Forest reserves
    - Forest reserves, grazing permits
    - General information
    - Hailey Land Office, Hailey, Idaho
    - Hetch-Hetchy matter (Box 531)
    - Homesteads
      - Amendment to three-year law
      - Boise-Payette, Idaho, A-Z, (2 folders)
      - Coeur D'Alene, Idaho
      - Enlarged, A-Z, (5 folders)
      - Forest reserves
        - A-L
        - M-Z (Box 532)
      - General, A-Z, (6 folders)
      - Grazing
      - Marble Creek, Idaho
      - Minidoka, Idaho (Box 533)
      - Northern Pacific Railway
      - Washington Water Power Co.
    - Indian lands, Flathead
    - Indian reservation lands
    - Irrigation districts
    - Lewiston Land Office, Lewiston, Idaho
    - Mines and mining
    - Minidoka, Idaho project
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous complaints and suggestions
    - National parks (Box 534)
    - Phosphate and coal lands
    - Power sites, Reservation Act
    - Railroad lands
    - Reclamation law, general, (2 folders)
    - Roads, rights of way
    - Scrip
    - State lands
    - Surveys
    - Timber claims
    - Topeka Land Office
    - Townsite matters
    - Water power development
  - 1914-1915 (Box 535)
    - Blackfoot Land Office
    - Boise, Idaho, project
    - Carey lands
    - Contests
    - Desert entries, A-Z, (2 folders)
    - Forest reserves, grazing permits
    - General information
    - Hailey Land Office, Hailey, Idaho
    - Homesteads
      - Boise-Payette, A-H
      - Enlarged, A-Z, (3 folders)
      - Forest reserve, A-Z, (2 folders) (Box 536)
      - General, A-Z, (3 folders)
      - Grazing
      - Minidoka, Idaho
      - Northern Pacific Railway
      - Three-year law
      - Washington Water Power Co.
    - Homesteads
    - Indian reservation land
    - Irrigation districts
    - Leasing legislation
    - Mines and mining
    - Minidoka, Idaho, reclamation project (Box 537)
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous complaints and suggestions
    - National parks
    - Power sites
    - Railroad lands
    - Reclamation law, general
    - Rights of way
    - Script
    - Stone and timber entry
    - Surveys
    - Timber claims
    - Townsite matters
    - Water Power Development
  - 1915-1916
    - Black Canyon, Idaho, project
    - Blackfoot Land Office
    - Boise Land Office, Boise, Idaho
    - Boise, Idaho, project
    - Carey lands
    - Claims (Box 538)
    - Contents
    - Desert
      - Entries
      - Land entries, A-Z
      - Land law
    - Drainage
    - Forest reserve
      - General
      - Grazing
    - Grazing matters
    - Hailey Land Office, Hailey, Idaho
    - Homesteads
      - Boise, Idaho, project, A-Z
      - Enlarged, A-Z, (2 folders)
      - Forest reserve, A-Z, (2 folders) (Box 539)
      - General, A-Z, (3 folders)
      - Grazing
      - Minidoka
      - Power sites
      - Three-year law
    - Indian reservation lands (Box 540)
    - Irrigation districts
    - Mines and mining
    - Minidoka, Idaho, project
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous complaints and suggestions
    - National parks
    - Power sites, reservoirs (Box 541)
    - Railroad lands
    - Railroad laws
    - Reclamation law, general
    - Right of way, roads
    - Scrip
    - Sheep Station, Idaho, lands
    - State lands
    - Surveys
    - Townsite matters
    - Water power development
  - 1916-1917
    - Boise, Idaho, project
    - Carey lands
    - Claims
    - Contests (Box 542)
    - Desert land entries, A-Z
    - Drainage
    - Forest reserves
      - General
      - Grazing permits
      - Pocatello Park, Idaho
    - Fort Hall, Idaho, tract
    - Homesteads
      - Boise, Idaho, project
      - Enlarged, A-Z, (2 folders)
      - Enlarged law
      - Forest Reserve, A-Z, (2 folders)
      - General, A-Z, (2 folders)
      - Grazing law, (2 folders) (Box 543)
      - Marble Creek, Idaho
      - Minidoka, Idaho
      - Power sites
    - Indian reservation lands
    - Irrigation districts
      - Black Canyon, Idaho, (2 folders)
      - General
      - Hillcrest
      - King Hill
      - Law
    - Mines and mining
    - Miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box 544)
    - Miscellaneous complaints and suggestions
    - National parks
    - Power sites, reservoirs
    - Railroad lands
      - Boise, Idaho, project
      - Dubois, Idaho, project
      - General
      - Minidoka, Idaho, project
    - Right-of-way
    - Scrip
    - Sheep Station, Idaho, land
    - State lands
    - Surveys
    - Townsites matters
    - Waterpower development
  - 1917-1918
    - Black Canyon, Idaho, project
    - Boise, Idaho
      - Park
      - Project
    - Carey lands
    - Contests
    - Desert land entries, A-Z
    - Drainage
      - General
      - Kootenai, Idaho
      - Pend D'Oreille, Idaho
    - Forest Reserves
      - General
      - Grazing permits
    - Forest Hall, Idaho, project
    - Grazing lands (Box 545)
    - Homesteads
      - Boise, Idaho, project
      - Enlarged, A-Z, (2 folders)
      - Forest reserve, A-Z
      - General, A-Z, (4 folders)
      - Grazing
      - Power sites (Box 546)
    - Indian reservation lands
    - Irrigation district
    - Leasing system
    - Mines and mining
    - Minidoka, Idaho, project
    - Miscellaneous complaints and suggestions, (2 folders)
    - Power sites
    - Railroad lands
    - Reclamation
    - Reservoirs and right-of-way
    - Snake River power site
    - Water power
  - 1918-1919
    - Bear Valley, Idaho, project
    - Carey lands
    - Claims
    - Contests (Box 547)
    - Desert land entries
    - Drainage
    - Drainage, Pend D'Oreille, Idaho
    - Forest Reserves
      - General
      - Grazing
    - Homesteads
      - Boise, Idaho, project
      - Enlarged
      - Forest reserve
      - General, A-Z, (2 folders)
      - Grazing
      - Minidoka, Idaho, project (Box 548)
      - Power sites
    - Indian reservation lands
    - Mines and mining
    - Miscellaneous
    - National forest
    - National parks
    - Power sites
    - Railroad lands
    - Reclamation
      - Black Canyon, Idaho
      - Boise, Idaho, project
      - Dubois, Idaho, project
      - Fort Hall, Idaho
      - General
      - Minidoka, Idaho, project
      - Other states
      - Proposed projects
    - Reservoirs, right-of-way
    - Roads
    - Soldiers and sailors settlements (Box 549)
    - Timber claims
    - Washington Water Power Co.
  - 1919-1920
    - Contests
    - Desert land entries, A-Z
    - Forest reserves
      - General
      - Grazing
    - General information
    - Homesteads
      - Boise, Idaho, project
      - Enlarged
      - Forest reserve, A-Z
      - General, A-Z
      - Minidoka, Idaho, project
      - Power sites
      - Washington Water Power Co.
    - Indian reservation lands (Box 550)
    - Mines and mining
    - Miscellaneous
    - National parks
    - Reclamation
      - Boise, Idaho, project
      - Dubois, Idaho, project
      - Fall River, Idaho, project
      - Fort Hall, Idaho
      - General
      - Minidoka, Idaho, project
      - Proposed projects
      - Sunnyside, Idaho
    - Soliders and sailors settlements
    - Surveys
    - Town site matters
  - 1920-1921
    - Carey lands
    - Claims
    - Contests
    - Desert entries
    - Drainage (Box 551)
    - Forest reserves
    - Forest reserves, Lemhi, Idaho
    - Grazing permits
    - Hailey Land Office, Hailey, Idaho
    - Homesteads
      - Boise, Idaho, project
      - Enlarged
      - Forest reserve
      - General, A-Z, (2 folders)
      - Stockraising
    - Indian lands
    - Irrigation districts
    - Mines and mining
    - Mines and mining (Box 552)